[Leorio] Yeah. It looks real.
And there’s a video attached to it.
We’ve got two targets.
A man and a woman.
I’ll head out right now,
so you just meet me there.
[Gon] Got it.
-Come on. Let’s go!
-Okay.
[theme song playing]
PURSUIT X AND X ANALYSIS
[narrator] Following a tip
about the Phantom Troupe,
Gon and his friends move out.
Once there, they encounter
Machi and Nobunaga.
But the pair is not simply waiting around
to be caught.
What do you think?
Did Uvo really get himself killed?
Probably, yeah.
Uvo may have been a brute,
but he wasn’t stupid.
I certainly can’t disagree with you there.
[Nobunaga] It didn’t matter
how tough his opponent was,
he always had the wits and experience
to prevail.
[phone ringing]
[woman] Yeah, hello?
[Leorio] I’m the guy who posted the ad.
[woman] Well, you’re late! Where are you?
Please stop looking around.
We can see you, so don’t worry.
Is that them?
The couple right behind your boyfriend?
I’m wiring the money to your account.
Confirm receipt.
Really?
[woman] Let’s go! Come on!
[Machi] But Uvo didn’t come back
this time.
Has he ever been this late
without letting us know before?
You heard what he said, didn’t you?
He wasn’t coming back
‘til he settled the score
with the chain user.
Yeah, I heard. That’s why I said probably.
I didn’t say that I was sure he was dead.
[Nobunaga] That your hunch?
[Machi] Just a hunch.
[Nobunaga] Well… your hunches are right,
more often than not.
[Leorio] Okay.
We should decide our next move.
So how should we go about
capturing these two?
[Killua] We don’t.
Look, they’re way out of our league.
It’s not happening.
[yells] Oh, come on!
We won’t know until we try,
and besides,
why didn’t you mention this before?!
Stop yelling. They’ll notice us.
But it’s the truth.
I knew it as soon as I saw them.
A while back my dad killed a Spider
for a job.
-[Gon] Huh?
-What?
He doesn’t complain much…
but he said the job
wasn’t worth the price.
And that is the highest compliment
he gives a target.
He even got all of us together
and told us we should steer clear
of the Phantom Troupe.
But that was years ago,
so I thought we might stand a chance.
[Leorio] They can’t be that strong…
can they?
Just imagine if the people
sitting at that table
were both Hisokas.
I guess...
it’s safe to say that
that’s a lot more than we can handle.
Okay. So, what do you think
they’re doing here?
They’re dating.
It’s a date. Right?
Wait… Is it really?
[Killua] No, of course not.
They noticed that other couple
behind them.
I can tell they’re paying close attention
to their surroundings.
I thought they were just being cautious
since the Mafia’s after them.
But if that was the case,
they wouldn’t be sitting in a public area
like that.
Instead, they act like
they don’t have a care in the world.
They’re waiting
for someone to find them,
acting as bait
and trying to draw out their prey.
We’re being observed.
And they’re not amateurs.
[Nobunaga] Yeah.
I can’t tell where they are,
they’re watching us.
[Machi] Is it the chain user?
[Nobunaga] No idea.
But if it is,
the Boss gave us free reign
to do whatever we want.
I don’t know about you,
but I got the distinct impression
he wants us to recruit him.
Machi...
The Boss said to find him
and bring him back.
Those were our only orders.
Come on, you haven’t forgotten all
about the unspoken rule, have you?
“Alive or dead
and by any means necessary”?
You’re welcome
to interpret the Boss’s orders
any way you see fit,
but you can’t force me
into agreeing with you.
Don’t put words in my mouth, all right?
Besides, you’re the one forcing the issue.
The atmosphere has changed.
I’m getting a bad feeling…
Do you think they noticed us?
Not yet.
We’re still in the clear.
You sure about that?
Remember, I can’t use Zetsu
to mask my presence
like the two of you.
Zetsu would attract attention,
so we can’t use it here.
They can sense Nen,
but they aren’t trying.
They’re looking at people in the area
trying to find anyone who acts suspicious.
Be careful.
And wipe those looks off your faces.
Just act natural.
[fake chuckling]
[Killua] You know what? Forget it.
[Nobunaga] Let’s decide,
right here and now.
Are we going to take him dead,
or try to bring him in alive?
Oh, all right.
Heads.
Tails, then.
HIRUMA MANSION
[Chrollo] Her?
[Shalnark] Yeah.
She’s Nostrade’s daughter.
Her name’s Neon.
According to the information
on the Hunter Website,
the chain user we’re looking
for is one of her bodyguards.
As for the rest of her bodyguards,
we have pictures and names
for these five here.
[Chrollo] This girl…
she’s responsible for Nostrade’s success?
[Shalnark] Most likely.
The info’s on the Hunter website,
so it should be accurate.
[Nostrade] I see.
So that’s what happened.
Getting a new room was a smart move.
The Phantom Troupe
is using the Hunter website;
there’s absolutely no doubt about it.
Neon wouldn’t be safe right now
without your quick thinking.
Thank you.
Now, first things first,
we need to transport
my daughter home urgently.
Is that all right with you, Neon?
It sounds like I don’t have a choice.
With the auction canceled,
I don’t see any point in being here.
And that makes me sad,
because I really wanted to go to that…
They’ll hold another auction
next year, pumpkin.
So, don’t be sad.
And I promise I’ll recover the items
you wanted from those bandits,
if it’s the last thing I do!
[Neon] Really?
Of course, my dear, I promise.
And have I ever in your life
broken a promise to you?
[Neon] Well, yeah…
More than you’ve kept!
[Nostrade laughs]
[Nostrade] All right, you got me.
[chuckles]
Your names are Melody and Basho, yes?
-Yes.
You two take Neon
back to the mansion immediately.
Be safe.
I want you both wearing simple disguises.
Now, Neon.
Go back to your room
and pack up your things.
[Neon] Okay.
[Nostrade] All right.
Let’s get down to business.
The Underground Auction
will be resuming tonight.
[all five] huh?
[Nostrade] The time and place
haven’t changed.
The community must demonstrate
that they will not
be intimidated by anyone.
The Ten Dons have vowed to recover
all of the stolen merchandise.
[Kurapika] But… sir…
As I mentioned earlier,
the man we captured gave up information.
He claimed that a Shadow Beast
took everything
before they even arrived.
Yes, that much is true.
However, all of the Shadow Beasts
are dead.
[both gasp]
[Nostrade] Nine bodies
have been recovered.
The final member, the Owl,
was the one
in charge of transporting the merchandise.
He was probably captured by the Troupe.
The Ten Dons understand
how frightening Nen can be.
If a Troupe member
can compel a confession,
they won’t need to resort to torture.
We think the merchandise the Owl took
has fallen into the Troupe’s hands.
So, as I was just saying,
with all the Shadow Beasts destroyed,
the Ten Dons will hire pros
to handle the Troupe.
Sir?
[Nostrade] The Mafia uses murder
as a tool of intimidation
but it’s not our area of expertise.
Considering the nature of our opponents,
it would be wise for us
to leave it to the experts.
We’ll have them crush the Troupe
on our behalf,
while avoiding further losses ourselves.
However, it’s a chance for us
to build our reputation.
We can’t allow the assassins
to take all the credit.
And so, Kurapika,
I want you to join the assassin team.
[Chrollo] Take care of the chain user
for me.
[Shalnark] Will do.
[Killua] They’re on the move.
Now what?
Like I said,
we can't beat them in a fight.
We’ll figure out a way.
Failure’s not really an option.
He’s right.
We can’t leave empty-handed, not now.
Okay, fine.
But listen. Gon and I will track them.
But no matter what,
we can’t let them spot us.
Which means we’ll have to use Zetsu.
Got it?
Wow...
I can see them standing here
but I can’t sense them.
Hey, Gon. Promise me two things.
If they see us, we give up immediately
and retreat, no questions asked.
Same if I say further pursuit
is impossible for any other reason.
Okay?
[Gon] Okay.
[Killua] The signal to abort
will be one ring.
Make sure your phone is on vibrate.
If they split up, we follow the woman.
Leorio,
call Zepile and keep an eye
on the auction for us.
No problem.
I’m guessing you’ve never
tracked anyone before?
Oh, uh… Yeah, kinda.
I tracked Hisoka during the Exam.
Really? And he didn’t notice you?
No.
I shadowed him pretty much the whole day.
All right! Not too shabby!
That hurt! What did you hit me for?
[Killua] Huh? Oh, no reason.
Well, you shouldn’t have a problem, then.
Just be sure to stay
out of their field of vision,
no matter what.
Ok, ready to go?
[Gon and Leorio] Yeah!
[Killua] The targets have passed the plaza
and gone down a side street.
[Gon] Roger that.
Do you think they know we’re here?
[Killua] It’s fine.
We’re using Zetsu,
so they won’t unless something goes wrong.
But they’re expecting someone
to follow them,
so be careful.
Okay. You too, Killua.
Ugh... He’s really telling me
to be careful?
I’m the one on high alert,
looking for changes in their behavior!
Good.
They haven’t noticed us.
When they realize we’re here,
they’re bound to react somehow.
They can try to hide it,
but their faces or gestures
will give them away.
I’ve been playing life-or-death games
of ‘shadow’
ever since I was three.
I won’t lose sight of them.
I can’t!
Are we being followed?
Yes, most likely.
It’s a pretty good bet, anyway.
Guess they know what they’re doing.
I don’t sense a damn thing.
They must be quite skilled.
[Killua] Damn, they’re moving
toward a deserted part of the city.
Maybe they figured out
they’re being followed.
So, could this be a trap?
No…
They don’t know our exact locations.
Unless they don’t know
they’re being followed
and they’re heading back to their hideout.
That’d be a huge win for us.
So, a trap...
or their hideout?
Which is it?
If it’s a trap, we bail.
Hideout, we keep following them.
There’s nothing unnatural
in their behavior.
We keep going!
Our stalker isn’t taking the bait.
Which means that it’s probably
not the chain user.
[Machi] Why’s that?
[Nobunaga] I can sense
multiple people tailing us
but the chain user…
probably works alone.
[Machi] Think so?
Yeah, he works as a bodyguard
for the Nostrade family, right?
Yet he managed to defeat Uvo
completely on his own,
and that’s no easy task.
But the Mafia hasn’t taken any action,
which supports my theory.
If they were responsible,
they’d be using Uvo to threaten us
whether he was dead or alive.
Not to mention the news
would probably be all over the web by now.
Since it’s not the chain user
probably defeated Uvo alone,
without ever reporting it to the Mafia.
Doesn’t make sense.
Why would someone with ties to the Mafia
work alone?
Probably a personal grudge.
“Probably”, huh?
You’ve been saying that a lot.
Oh, shut up.
If he went out seeking revenge
without Mafia backup,
I doubt that he’d be
teaming up with someone else.
Thus, the chain user works alone.
The group following us
is totally unrelated.
Impressive how full of holes
your logic is.
Okay, fine then Let’s hear what you think.
All right.
If you really must know…
I suspect that there’s a link
between these guys and the chain user.
Hunch again?
It is.
You’ve gotta be kidding.
People who rely on their gut feelings
really shouldn’t criticize
someone else’s logic.
So, what do you think?
[Killua] They’re waiting for someone,
or trying to draw us out.
One or the other.
Yeah, but do you think
they know we’re following them?
[Killua] Right now, it’s fifty-fifty.
But they definitely don’t know
our location.
That’s why they’re trying to lure us out.
They want us to show ourselves.
[Gon] What do we do?
[Killua] They might be waiting
for someone else.
-Hold your position.
-[phone ringing]
Gon, I’m hanging up.
-Pay close attention
and if they react at all,
we’re gonna make a run for it.
And don’t stop!
The next time I ring it means we bail.
Yeah, I got it.
[Phinks] It’s Phinks.
Oh, what’s up, Phinks?
[Phinks] Just wanted to see
how you’re doing.
We were being followed for a while
but they haven’t made their move.
And we can’t locate them,
so this’ll take some time.
[Phinks] Oh, yeah?
Then how about a hint?
Wait, what are you talking about?
[gasping in shock]
[grunts]
A diversion?
Got him!!
He blocked it easily,
with his left hand!
[straining]
[Killua roars]
[whistles]
[Nobunaga] Hey.
[Killua gasps]
Hello, Phinks.
What are you doing here?
I swear I was told
that you were heading out with the Boss.
This is the fourth floor!
Well, like they say,
“deceive your allies
to deceive your enemies”.
[shrill chuckle]
Looks like the Boss got me good again.
Zetsu masters all over the place?
Guess I should’ve known…
They tailed us while we tailed them?
And our targets didn’t know?!
They tricked us!
[Nobunaga] So, kiddo…
I’ve got a couple of questions for you.
Do you know the chain user
and think before you answer.
He’s a Nen user who fights with chains.
We’re trying to find him.
Is he the one who asked you to follow us?
Was this his idea?
[Gon] I don’t know him.
We followed you two for our own reasons
and not anybody else’s.
I just need a split second,
an opening, to get away!
Your thoughts?
I just can’t tell...
If he’s lying, he’s certainly good at it.
Why don’t I check.
[Nobunaga] Question one:
Why were you following us?
Be concise.
A bad lie will make things worse.
Because the Mafia has put out
a huge bounty on your heads.
Websites are offering a lot of money
just for information on your whereabouts.
[Nobunaga] Question two:
Who taught you to track people?
I guess mainly...
I used a Nen ability
to hide myself called Zetsu.
See, I... want to be a pro Hunter.
Who taught you to do that?
It was a Shingen-ryu master.
And three:
Do you know a Nen user
who fights with chains?
Fights with chains?
[Nobunaga]
He’d be a Conjurer or Manipulator.
We want to know if your master
has chains hanging from his right arm.
Or is it you?
You should come clean right now if it is.
I really don’t know.
My master is an Enhancer and...
he just taught me
the four basic exercises, nothing more.
Well, that’s a pity.
If you don’t know, we got nothin.
It’s time for the last question.
I’ll give you two choices
but think carefully before you answer.
Do you want to die now or later?
It’s up to you.
You have three seconds.
[terrified breath]
[phone buzzing]
It’s no use. Don’t try anything.
Yes.
Understood. On our way.
Little boy.
That friend of yours
surrendered quietly.
[Pakunoda] I’ll ask again.
Do you know the chain user?
I already told you that before.
I don’t!
I see.
What about you, boy?
Do you have any guesses?
[tires screeching]
Welcome to our hideout.
[both gasp]
[narrator] Gon and Killua find themselves
standing inside the hideout
of the dreaded Phantom Troupe,
gripped by the anticipation
of what’s to come.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Machi!
She’s Phantom Troupe
and she’s a Transmuter!
She can turn her aura into Nen threads.
Her big technique is Nen stitches.
She can put your body back together!
[both] Just like this!
[Gon] Next time: “Ally x and x Sword”.
-Gotcha!
-[Killua buzzing like mosquito]
[Gon] Hey! Look! I caught it!
[Killua] That’s one of Milluki’s
mini-bombs!
[Gon and Killua] Ka-boom!